thebookseller.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy | The Bookseller

### **1\. Privacy Summary**

The Data Controller, The Bookseller Media Limited, a company registered in the United Kingdom (Registered No. 07201744) at Ashcombe Court, Woolsack Way, Godalming, Surrey GU7 1LQ, is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the ‘Act’) and the General Data Protection Regulation (the ‘GDPR’). If you have any questions about this policy, the representative responsible for Data Protection can be contacted by writing to Audience Marketing Manager, The Bookseller, 10th Floor, Westminster Tower, 3 Albert Embankment, London, SE1 7SP, or alternatively by sending an email to Kirstine Bowen at [kirstine.bowen@thebookseller.com](mailto:kirstine.bowen@thebookseller.com).

The Bookseller Media Limited is the incisive and independent source of business intelligence and analysis for the book trade. In order to operate the services we offer, The Bookseller Media Limited (‘The Bookseller’, ‘our’, ‘us’ or ‘we’), must ask you to provide us with information about yourself. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect and how we use that information. We take the processing of your information very seriously and will use your information only in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal data is referred to as ‘information’ which means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites and we recommend that you check the privacy policy of any other web sites you may visit. The inclusion of links to such web sites does not imply any endorsement of the material on such sites nor any association with their owners or operators. If you have any complaints relating to such sites, please contact them directly.

The Bookseller uses Google Analytics to analyse traffic to our websites. Google Analytics does not create individual profiles for visitors. You can learn more about Google Analytics and their privacy policy on their website. You can also opt out by installing the Analytics opt-out browser add-on.

The Bookseller does not disclose information about identifiable individuals to advertisers. Aggregate statistical information gathered from registration forms may be passed on to advertisers or others regarding sales or website usage. At no point will this include personal identifying information.

This Privacy Policy will be updated from time to time and all future changes will take effect as specified at the time of the update by posting a revised version of it on our website. Please check back regularly for the most current version of our Privacy Policy.

### **2\. Information We Collect**

To use any of our services, you must provide your name and email address and in some instances your company name, job title, postal address and telephone number. In order to make payments, you must provide credit card, debit card or bank account information. We do not collect any sensitive personal information such as information on your racial or ethnic origins, political opinions, trade union affiliations, sexual life, health or criminal history.

When you access our services online using any device, we collect and store device data including but not limited to geolocation data to provide offers relevant to your region. We also collect information such as which pages of our website you visit, IP addresses, the type of browser you use and the times you access our website.

We will only keep your information for as long as is necessary for the purpose of providing you with the service you have requested from us or to meet specific anti-fraud and legal requirements. If you would like more information, please contact the representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary.

The provision of the information detailed above is a requirement necessary to provide the service. By providing your information and signing up to our service you are entering a contract for the term of the service. If you object or are not willing to provide this information, please do not register or use any of our services.

When you access our website, or use any of our services, we (including companies we work with) may place small data files on your computer or other device known as cookies. For more information, please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.thebookseller.com/use-cookies).

### **3\. How We Use The Information We Collect**

Our primary purpose in collecting your information is to provide you with a service. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  * Provide the service to you;
  * Notify you about your service including reminding you when it is due to lapse; and
  * Carry out internal administration and analysis.

### **4\. How We Use The Information For Marketing**

We will only send you direct marketing communications in circumstances where we have your specific consent or where we believe we can demonstrate a legitimate interest. 

When you sign up to any of our services, we ask for your consent to send you direct marketing communication over a variety of channels. We will honour your right to withdraw your consent at any time.

When you enquire about or request a service from us, we may rely on our legitimate business interests to send you marketing communications (via post, email or telephone). These communications will always be related to our services and we believe will be of interest to you.  We will provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of this at any time. An example of this would be contacting previous business event attendees about the same event the following year. NB: We will only contact business contacts, and not consumers or sole traders when relying on our legitimate interests.

If you want to stop receiving direct marketing from us, you can use the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email you receive, amend your preferences by logging in to your Account on thebookseller.com, tell us when we call you or alternatively you can contact the representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary.

Periodically we conduct data profiling on the information we collect to better understand our customers in order to provide targeted communications which suit your needs. If you wish to stop your information being used for data profiling, please contact the representative responsible for Data Protection. Please note that a request to opt out of data profiling will automatically stop direct marketing from us and vice versa.

### **5\. How We Share Information With Third Parties**

We will not sell or rent your information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent.

However, just like most service providers, The Bookseller works with third parties who administer important functions for us that allow us to offer and enhance the services we provide. These providers, or Data Processors, are covered by an appropriate agreement and are located within the European Economic Area. Sometimes it will be necessary for us to disclose information required for the specific purpose to them so that the services can be performed and by requesting us to provide you with the services you consent to this disclosure.

We reserve the right to disclose to third parties your information to comply with applicable laws including but not limited to disclosure in accordance with the Act, the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 and lawful authority requests, to safeguard the proper operation of our systems and to protect ourselves and the companies we work with.

The Data Processors that The Bookseller currently works with to enhance the services we provide include, but are not limited to: Access, Adestra, Buxton Press, ESco, Epaqo, Eventsforce, Salesforce, Spatial, [VE Interactive](https://www.ve.com/privacy-policy). Please contact us for the most up-to-date list, if required.

In some of our newsletters, The Bookseller may include banner advertising or advertorials from third parties, though, as stated, we will not pass on your information to third parties for their marketing purposes. Emails that include third party advertising include, but are not limited to, the Morning Briefing, FutureBook, Rights, Books in the Media and Sneak Peek emails. If you do not wish to receive this third-party advertising, do not subscribe to these emails, or use an ad blocker on your email service provider.

### **6\. Information Security**

The Bookseller is committed to handling your information with high standards of information security. We collect, store and process your information on servers primarily located in the United Kingdom but also elsewhere in the European Economic Area. We use safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, we enforce physical access controls to our buildings and files and we authorise access to personal information only for those employees who require it to fulfil their job responsibilities. Our site uses industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to allow for the encryption of information during transmissions to our servers. These security measures mean that we may occasionally have to ask you for proof of identity before we are able to disclose personal information to you; however, there will be no administration charge for such a request.

In the event of any data breach, we will issue a notification to the statutory authority, the Information Commissions Office, and will strive to contact you, if the data is applicable to you, within 72 hours of being made aware of such a breach.

### **7\. Accessing, Deleting Or Updating Your Information**

#### **Accessing Your Information**

You can access the personal information you have provided us by making a Subject Access Request to the representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary. Upon receipt and following any necessary proof of identification checks, Subject Access Requests will be responded to within one calendar month.

#### **Deleting Your Information**

A request to have the personal information you have provided us removed from our systems can be made at any time to the representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary. Your information will be removed from our systems except in circumstances where we are required to retain this information for compliance with legal obligation or for future suppression purposes, where the minimal amount necessary will be retained in order to honour an individual’s right.

#### **Updating Your Information**

You can review the personal information and email preferences that you have provided us and make any desired changes or rectifications at any time either online or by contacting the representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary. To amend your personal information or email preferences online, please log in to your Account on thebookseller.com and edit these details on the ‘My Account’ tab.

**There will be no administrative charge for fulfilling any of the requests above.**

### **8\. Information Regarding Children**

Children are not eligible to use any service we offer and we ask that minors (persons under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us.

### **9\. Accountability**

We will process your personal data for the purposes set out in this policy. However, if you have any queries or requests in relation to Data Protection or this Privacy Policy please notify our representative responsible for Data Protection using the details available in the Privacy Summary. Alternatively, if you have any concerns about our information rights practices that our representative responsible for Data Protection was unable to address sufficiently, you may report these to our statutory authority, the Information Commissions Office: ico.org.uk.
